{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The condition that causes vapour locking in a brake system is", "opta": "overheating of the fluid due to frequent brake application", "optb": "overcooling of the brakes during high speed driving", "optc": "keeping the vehicle without use for an extended period", "optd": "an excessively high engine speed on a downhill road", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The portion of a crankshaft which rests on cylinder block is called main journal.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A baffle plate is fitted inside the oil pan to prevent the oil from splashing when it is subjected to vibration and other movement during vehicle operation.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The motion of the cam is transferred to the valves through", "opta": "pistons", "optb": "rocker arms", "optc": "camshaft pulley", "optd": "valve stems", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following symptom is caused as a result of brake disc run out ?", "opta": "Ineffectiveness of the brakes", "optb": "Judder during braking", "optc": "Localized wearing of the brake pads", "optd": "Rapid wearing of the brake pads", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the engine coolant leaks into the engine oil, then engine oil", "opta": "appears milky", "optb": "becomes foamy", "optc": "turns black", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The function of an alternator in an automobile is to", "opta": "supply electric power", "optb": "convert mechanical energy into electrical energy", "optc": "continually recharge the battery", "optd": "partly convert engine power into electric power", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A clutch is usually designed to transmit maximum torque which is", "opta": "equal to the maximum engine torque", "optb": "80 per cent of the maximum engine torque", "optc": "150 per cent of the maximum engine torque", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of bearing is used for main bearings and connecting rod bearings ?", "opta": "Ballbearings", "optb": "Plain bearings", "optc": "Needle roller bearing", "optd": "Taper roller bearing", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is necessary to maintain the valve clearances as they", "opta": "reduce the resistance to sliding that occurs between the cam and the tappet", "optb": "allow for lengthening of the valves owing to the heat of combustion", "optc": "increase the speed at which the valves move up and down", "optd": "make the crankshaft turn smoothly", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Incorrect steering axis inclination (S.A.I.) causes", "opta": "tendency to assume toe-out orientation", "optb": "generation of a braking effect at tight corners", "optc": "poor recovery of the steering wheel after making a turn", "optd": "the vehicle to pull to the side of lesser inclination", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a unit type body (frameless body) design, the sheet metal parts are welded together, forming a frame work to which outer skin is attached.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The torque available at the contact between driving wheels and road is known as", "opta": "brake effort", "optb": "tractive effort", "optc": "clutch effort", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A traction control system (TCS) in automobiles controls the", "opta": "vibrations on the steering wheel", "optb": "engine power during acceleration", "optc": "torque that is transmitted by the tyres to the road surface", "optd": "stopping distance in case of emergency", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In radial tyres", "opta": "one ply layer runs diagonally one way and another layer runs diagonally the other way", "optb": "all plies run parallel to one another and vertical to tyre bead", "optc": "inner tubes are always used", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The oil pump is driven by the", "opta": "camshaft", "optb": "alternator shaft", "optc": "crankshaft via drive belt", "optd": "crankshaft directly", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a spark plug, when the temperature of the central electrode exceeds a certain temperature, any carbon that has adhered will be burnt off, and the temperature at which this burning off carbon starts is referred to as the self cleaning temperature.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The flywheel and the pressure plate bind the clutch disc between them so that the engine and the transmission can be engaged.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The vehicle ride will be comfortable if", "opta": "unsprung mass is kept minimum", "optb": "sprang mass is kept minimum", "optc": "vehicle mass is kept minimum", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The main function of intake manifold is that it", "opta": "promotes the mixture of air and fuel", "optb": "reduces intake noise", "optc": "cools the intake air to a suitable temperature", "optd": "distributes intake air equally to the cylinders", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Positive camber is used to compensate for wheels tilting inward due to the weight of the vehicle.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In automobiles G.V.W. refers to", "opta": "gross vehicle width", "optb": "gross vehicle weight", "optc": "gross vehicle wheel base", "optd": "gross vehicle wheel track", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The firing order for an in-line four cylinder I.C. engine is", "opta": "1-2-3-4", "optb": "1-3-4-2", "optc": "1-2-4-3", "optd": "1-3-2-4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a ventilated disc brake,", "opta": "a duct directs air towards the caliper for cooling while the vehicle is moving", "optb": "caliper is covered with cooling fins", "optc": "disc contains many small holes for optimum cooling performance", "optd": "disc contains radial vanes between its rubbing surfaces for optimum cooling performance", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The effect of having excess camber is", "opta": "excessive steering alignment torque", "optb": "hard steering", "optc": "too much traction", "optd": "uneven tyre wear", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the air-fuel mixture in a spark ignition engine is too rich, then air-fuel ratio is about", "opta": "17:1", "optb": "15:1", "optc": "13:1", "optd": "10:1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The advantage of double-wishbone suspension design is that a large amount of freedom is available for setting geometry and precise settings can be made for driving comfort and steerability,", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The co-efficient of rolling resistance for a truck weighing 63 500 N is 0.018. The rolling resistance to the truck is", "opta": "1.143 N", "optb": "11.43 N", "optc": "114.3 N", "optd": "1143 N", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the level of tension in the belt is too high, it can result in a loss of power or in bending of the rotating shaft or crankshaft.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the air-fuel mixture ignites before the spark takes place at spark plug, the condition is called", "opta": "detonation", "optb": "ignition", "optc": "pre-ignition", "optd": "rumble", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The information provided by the oxygen (O2) sensor to the feedback control system is about the", "opta": "air-fuel ratio", "optb": "air temperature", "optc": "air flow speed", "optd": "exhaust gas volume", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The diagram which shows the correct crank positions corresponding to the opening and closing of the valves, is known as", "opta": "indicator diagram", "optb": "axial force diagram", "optc": "valve timing diagram", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference between DOT 3 and DOT 4 brake fluids is", "opta": "DOT 4 fluid has a higher boiling point than DOT 3 fluid", "optb": "DOT 4 fluid has a lower boiling point than DOT 3 fluid", "optc": "DOT 3 and DOT 4 fluids have the same boiling point, but DOT 4 fluid has a longer service life", "optd": "DOT 4 fluid is more resistant to freezing than DOT 3 fluid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The battery is an electrochemical device, which means battery", "opta": "makes chemicals by mechanical means", "optb": "uses chemical action to provide electricity", "optc": "has curved plates instead of flat plates", "optd": "does not use an electrolyte", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The operation of removing trapped air from the hydraulic braking system is known as", "opta": "trapping", "optb": "tapping", "optc": "bleeding", "optd": "cleaning", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The aluminium alloy is used in cylinder blocks because", "opta": "it is lighter and have good heat dissipation characteristics", "optb": "material cost is low", "optc": "it does not require any cylinder liners", "optd": "the piston is also made of aluminium alloy", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a fuel injection system, the electronic control module (ECM) calculates the optimum fuel-injection volume for the engine condition based on the data received from the sensors, and injects this volume of fuel into the intake manifold at the optimum timing.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The tilting of the front wheels away from the vertical, when viewed from the front of the car, is called", "opta": "camber", "optb": "caster", "optc": "toe-in", "optd": "toe-out", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The main function of the tread pattern on tyre is that", "opta": "the tread grooves pass air between the tyre and road surface, thereby preventing tyre from overheating", "optb": "the crests between the tread grooves absorb road noise", "optc": "in wet conditions, the tread grooves expel water that is drawn between the tyre and road surface", "optd": "the tread pattern protects the tyre's inner carcass from small stones and pieces of glass", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The compression ratio in petrol engine is kept less than in Diesel engine because", "opta": "it makes petrol engines lighter", "optb": "higher or equivalent compression ratio in petrol engines is not possible due to pre-ignition", "optc": "less compression ratio gives better performance", "optd": "it is just customary to have less compression ratio in petrol engines", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most commonly used supplementary restraint system (SRS) component is", "opta": "seat belt", "optb": "brake", "optc": "airbag", "optd": "steering", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The natural gas is compressed in a CNG cylinder at a pressure of", "opta": "200 bar", "optb": "220 bar", "optc": "250 bar", "optd": "300 bar", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cetane rating of Diesel fuel is in the order of", "opta": "25", "optb": "45", "optc": "70", "optd": "90", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The air gap between the central electrode and ground (or side) electrode of a spark plug is around", "opta": "0.2 mm", "optb": "0.5 mm", "optc": "1 mm", "optd": "1.5 mm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cetane number of a Diesel fuel is a measure of", "opta": "volatility", "optb": "viscosity", "optc": "ignition quality", "optd": "delay peirod", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The valve overlap in four stroke petrol engines is approximately", "opta": "30\u00b0", "optb": "60\u00b0", "optc": "90\u00b0", "optd": "120\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The petrol engines are also known as", "opta": "spark ignition (S.I.) engines", "optb": "compression ignition (C.I.) engines", "optc": "steam engines", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following indicates a multigrade oil ?", "opta": "SAE 30", "optb": "API SF", "optc": "SAE 20 W-50", "optd": "API 50", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The coefficient of friction for the clutch facing is approximately", "opta": "0.1", "optb": "0.4", "optc": "0.8", "optd": "1.2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The component that connects the steering rack to the knuckles is", "opta": "tie-rod", "optb": "sector gear", "optc": "pivot", "optd": "spline", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}